{"tossups": [{"question": "A slave named Ben claimed to have found this man\u2019s dead body surrounded by sixteen corpses, one of which had this man\u2019s knife stuck in it. This man\u2019s loss in an 1835 Congressional election prompted him to tell his statesmen that \u201cthey might go to hell, and I would go to Texas.\u201d This man joined William Travis in disobeying an order by Sam Houston to abandon a San Antonio mission. For ten points, name this man who died defending the Alamo, a legendary frontiersman from Tennessee.", "answer": "David \u201cDavy\u201d<b> Crockett</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "The creation of this route was documented in the Kaiheji. Older predecessors of this route include the Hong Gou and Han Gou. The city of Kaifeng became a major commercial hub due to this route. Disruptions along this route could be seen as a loss of the Mandate of Heaven. Work on this route began during the Spring and Autumn Period, and it was fully connected during the Sui Dynasty to ship grain and expedite trade. For ten points, name this great work of Chinese infrastructure that starts in Beijing and connects the Yellow and Yangtze Rivers, the longest canal in the world.", "answer": "Beijing-Hangzhou<b> Grand Canal</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A claim involving this woman was popularized by a 1974 biography written by Fawn M. Brodie and was further developed in the late 20th and early 21st centuries by Annette Gordon-Reed. This woman\u2019s children, including Beverley, Madison, and Eston, have no records of a second parent in a contemporary Farm Book. This woman accompanied the girl Polly to live in France for five years beginning in 1784. For ten points, name this slave who probably had several children with Thomas Jefferson.", "answer": "Sally<b> Hemings</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "The first time that Rome attacked Illyria was meant to stop a supporter of these people named Teuta. These people were supposed to help guide the slaves of Spartacus to safety, but deserted them prior to the Battle of the Siler River. Pompey was granted great powers to fight these people in the Lex Gabinia, and a number of these people were crucified after they held a young Julius Caesar for ransom. Cilicia was a Roman-era stronghold of, for ten points, what seafaring marauders?", "answer": "<b> pirate</b>s", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "Suetonius noted how this figure owned a \u201ccollar of stones\u201d and a \u201ctroop of slaves and furniture.\u201d To disprove a prophecy made by Thrasyllus of Mendes, grain barges were used to create a bridge across the Bay of Baiae for this figure to travel on. This figure, who had a name meaning \u201cswift,\u201d was owned by the brother of Drusilla; because that man was assassinated in 41 AD, this figure never ended up becoming consul. For ten points, name this horse that was beloved by Caligula.", "answer": "<b> Incitatus</b> (prompt on Caligula\u2019s horse before \u201chorse\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "The first member of this group wrote a poetry collection,<em> Asa di Var</em>, that was compiled by another member of this group, Arjan Dev. The tenth member of this group initiated the five Panj Pyare into the Khalsa. Members of this group include Amar Das and a man born Gobind Rai. The final member of this group is, and will eternally be, the Adi Granth, a religious text. Nanak was the first of, for ten points, what group of 11 sources of guidance for Sikhs?", "answer": "Sikh<b> guru</b>s (prompt on Sikhs before mentioned)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "One holder of this position tried to stop Richard Olney from stopping the Pullman Strike. John Peter Altgeld held this position in the 19th century, while Otto Kerner and George Ryan held it in the 20th century. While serving in this position, Rod Blagojevich [blah-goy-eh-vich] was arrested for corruption related to the \u201csale\u201d of President-elect Obama\u2019s vacated Senate seat. Bruce Rauner currently holds, for ten points, what leadership position in the \u201cLand of Lincoln?\u201d", "answer": "<b> Governor of Illinois</b> (prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Alexander Neckham\u2019s<em> On the Nature of Things</em> provides the earliest European account of these devices.<em> The Dream Pool Essays</em> describes how wax was attached to the center of a component of these devices that was then hung from a strain of silk. These devices, which were originally used for divination in<em> feng shui</em>, are one of the Four Great Inventions of China, and they were adapted for maritime use to provide direction during cloudy weather. For ten points, name this navigational device that contains a magnetic needle.", "answer": "<b> compass</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "After the election, this man worked as an informal representative to the UK for Roosevelt.", "answer": "Wendell<b> Willkie</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s most famous advisor broke off his teeth to assure his mother that power would not change him. Though this man may have assassinated the satraps Nicanor and Philip, he received the Greek ambassador Megasthenes and influenced the Battle of Ipsus by giving 300 war elephants to Seleucus. This man allegedly met his end by fasting to death in a Jain ceremony. The<em> Arthashastra</em> was written by Kautilya an advisor to this man. For ten points, name this ruler who, as a teenager, defeated the Nanda dynasty to unite India and found the Mauryan empire.", "answer": "<b> Chandragupta</b> Maurya", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "The first of Peter Hebblethwaite\u2019s two papal biographies focuses on this man. Sedevacantism holds that the last valid pope was succeeded by this man. This pope issued a bull addressed to \u201call men of good will\u201d that advocated for nuclear non-proliferation. This author of<em> Pacem in Terris</em> and successor to Pius XII convened a council that produced the<em> Dignitatus Humanae</em> and allowed for the mass to be performed in the vernacular. For ten points, name this pope who convened the Second Vatican Council in 1959.", "answer": "Pope Saint<b> John XXIII</b> [23] (accept<b> Ioannes XXIII</b>; accept<b> Giovanni XXIII</b>; accept Angelo Giuseppe<b> Roncalli</b>; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A painting created and set in this city shows a woman in a black dress shielding her eyes from a doctor making an incision in a patient\u2019s thigh. This city was the home of Thomas Eakins, who painted<em> The Gross</em> <em>Clinic</em>. Another painting set in this city shows Roger Sherman, Robert Livingston, and Thomas Jefferson presenting the title document to John Hancock. For ten points, name this city where John Trumbull\u2019s <em>Declaration of Independence</em> is set.", "answer": "<b> Philadelphia</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "In response to revelations regarding NSA surveillance, this country\u2019s leader said that \u201cthe Internet is uncharted territory for us all.\u201d Former President of European Parliament Martin Schulz announced his intentions to run as the Social Democratic Candidate in October 2017 elections in this country. Recep Erdogan [aird-oh-wan] accused this country of \u201cNazi practices\u201d after pro-Erdogan rallies were cancelled in Frechen and Cologne. For ten points, name this country led by the Christian Democratic Union under Chancellor Angela Merkel.", "answer": "<b> Germany</b> (or<b> Deutschland</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>A piece of music depicting this city calls for six buccina, though flugelhorns are normally used. A carnival in this city was the subject of a concert overture adapted from</b><em><b> Benvenuto </b><b>Cellini</b></em><b> by Hector Berlioz. Another work depicting this city includes a recording of a (+) nightingale in its \u201cJaniculum\u201d section. This city titled a French scholarship that was abolished in 1968 and entitled the winner to stay at the (*)</b> Villa Medici. For ten points, a work depicting the \u201cPines\u201d of what city, by Ottorino Respighi, ends with a depiction of legions marching down the Appian Way?", "answer": "<b> Rome</b> (accept Pines of<b> Rome</b>; accept Prix de<b> Rome</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>This man adopted the name John Hume Ross so that he could join the RAF without fanfare. The Battle of Maysaloun undid the provisional government of the Emir Faisal, which</b> <b>had been set up by this man. He was captured at (+)</b> <b>Daraa while under the command of</b> <b>Edmund Allenby. This man worked with Auda ibu Tayi in seizing Aqaba shortly after being sent to reconnoiter the (*)</b> Hejaz. In 1918, this man captured Damascus from the Ottoman Empire, an event recounted in his autobiographical<em> Seven Pillars of Wisdom</em>. For ten points, name this British leader of the Arab Revolt during World War I.", "answer": "Thomas Edward<b> Lawrence</b> (or<b> Lawrence</b> of Arabia)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man worked to distribute American surplus internationally as the first director of\u201cFood for Peace.\u201d This man worked with Donald Fraser to establish a commission increasing the number of caucuses and primaries. Along with Mark (+) Hatfield, this man attempted to propose legislation ending the Vietnam War. After running mate Thomas Eagleton was discovered to have undergone (*) </b> electric shock therapy, this presidential candidate carried only Massachusetts. For ten points, name this South Dakota senator who lost the 1972 presidential election to Richard Nixon.", "answer": "George<b> McGovern</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This actor starred in a film based on Daisy Suckley\u2019s diaries; in that film, 2012\u2019s</b><em><b> Hyde </b><b>Park on Hudson</b></em><b>, this man played FDR. This actor tried speaking English with a Nazi</b> <b>as Richard Campbell in</b><em><b> The Monuments Men</b></em><b>. After the 2016 (+)</b> <b>World Series, this</b> <b>actor sneaked in to honk the horn of MVP Ben Zobrist\u2019s new car. This actor\u2019s only Oscar nomination came in 2003 for playing Bob Harris in (*)</b><em> Lost in Translation</em>. For ten points, name this actor whose less historic and more comedic roles include Carl Spackler and Dr. Peter Venkman in <em>Caddyshack</em> and<em> Ghostbusters</em>, respectively.", "answer": "William James \u201cBill\u201d<b> Murray</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}